What they needed was a country big enough for their dreams.
Far and Away is a adventure, drama, romance film directed by Ron Howard.
A young couple escapes Ireland, dreaming of a new life
during the land giveaway in Oklahoma.
As they struggle to survive against betrayal and harsh winter conditions, they
must fend off her parents who are determined to bring her back home.
Joseph Donnelly, played by Tom Cruise.
Shannon Christie, played by Nicole Kidman.
Stephen Chase, played by Thomas Gibson.
Daniel Christie, played by Robert Prosky.
Nora Christie, played by Barbara Babcock.
Danty Duff, played by Cyril Cusack.
Far and Away is a 1992 American epic Western romantic adventure drama film directed by Ron
Howard from a screenplay by Bob Dolman and a story by Howard and Dolman.
It stars Tom Cruise and Nicole Kidman.
This was the last cinematography credit for Mikael Salomon
before he moved on to a directing career.
The music score was by John Williams.
It was screened out of competition at the 1992 Cannes Film Festival.
Cruise and Kidman, who were married at the time, play Irish immigrants seeking their
fortune in the 1890s America, eventually taking part in the Land Run of 1893.
This was Cyril Cusack's final film before his death the following year.
The film explores themes of bare knuckle boxing, father murder,
brothel, suspicion of murder, american dream.
The tone is emotional and intense.